A Finding Aid to the Samuel J. Wagstaff Papers, circa 1932-1985, in the Archives of American Art AAA.wagssamu
Archives of American Art
Samuel J. Wagstaff papers
circa 1932-1985
AAA.wagssamu
Archives of American Art
6.2 Linear feet
The Samuel J. Wagstaff papers, circa 1932-1985 comprise 6.2 linear feet of correspondence, writings, miscellaneous records, printed material, and photographs documenting Wagstaff's professional and personal relationships with artists and photographers, his career as an art curator, and his position as an important collector of paintings and photographs. Correspondence with artists and others such as curators, arts organizations, galleries, and museums, reflects the diversity of contemporary American art and includes individuals associated with the abstract expressionist, Fluxus, pop, earth, conceptual, and minimalist art movements.
Wagstaff, Samuel J.
Provenance
Samuel J. Wagstaff donated his papers between 1976 and 1986.
Restrictions on Access
The collection has been digitized and is available online via AAA's website.
Alternative Forms Available
The papers of Samuel J. Wagstaff in the Archives of American Art were digitized in 2008, and total 7614 images.
Materials not digitized include books, reproductions, and sales catalogs.
Biographical Note
Samuel J. Wagstaff, Jr. (1921-1987), the son of a lawyer from an old New York family and fashion artist Olga Piorkowska, was born in New York City. A graduate of Yale University, he was an ensign in the Navy and took part in the D-day landing at Omaha Beach.
Following World War II, Wagstaff studied Renaissance art at the Institute of Fine Arts, New York University. A David E. Finley art history fellowship took him to the National Gallery of Art, Washington, D. C. in 1959. He served as curator of contemporary art at the Wadsworth Atheneum, Hartford, Conn., from 1961 to 1968, where he coordinated sculptor Tony Smith's first museum show in 1966. In 1971, during Wagstaff's tenure as curator at the Detroit Institute of Arts (1968-1971), he presented Michael Heizer's installation Dragged Mass Geometric on the grounds of the museum.
In addition to his curatorial work, Samuel J. Wagstaff was a noted collector. Originally, he was a fairly influential collector of avant-garde paintings. After seeing the exhibition "The Painterly Photograph" and meeting photographer Robert Mapplethorpe, Wagstaff became convinced that photographs were the most unrecognized and, possibly, the most valuable works of art. He moved to New York and began selling his collection of paintings, using the proceeds to begin his photography collection and concentrating on 19th century American, British, and French examples. Then, influenced by his lover, photographer Mapplethorpe, Wagstaff's taste veered toward the daring, and he began to depart from established names in search of new talent. His collection was soon recognized as one of the finest private holdings in the United States. An exhibition of his photographs was organized by the Corcoran Gallery of Art, Washington, D. C., in 1978, and A Book of Photographs from the Sam Wagstaff Collection was published to accompany the show that toured the country.
The photograph collection was sold to the J. Paul Getty Museum, Malibu, Calif., in 1984, for a reported $5 million. Wagstaff then focused his attention on collecting 19th century American silver, and a selection from that collection was exhibited at the New York Historical Society in 1987.
Samuel J. Wagstaff died in New York City on January 14, 1987, from pneumonia, a complication of HIV infection.
Scope and Content Note
The Samuel J. Wagstaff papers, circa 1932-1985, comprise 6.2 linear feet of correspondence, writings, miscellaneous records, printed material, and photographs documenting Wagstaff's professional and personal relationships with artists and photographers, his career as an art curator, and his position as an important collector of paintings and photographs.
Correspondence with artists and others such as curators, arts organizations, galleries, and museums reflects the diversity of contemporary American art and includes individuals associated with the abstract expressionist, Fluxus, pop, earth, conceptual, and minimalist art movements. Wagstaff's importance as a collector and curator and his generosity to and interest in artists is evident from the large number of invitations to view and critique work, requests for fellowship and grant recommendations, and thank you notes from artists to whom he extended financial or moral support. Among the most prolific correspondents found here are: Dan Basen, George Brecht, James Lee Byars, Walter de Maria, Mark Di Suvero, Albert Fine, Dan Flavin, Ann Halprin, Grace Hartigan, Charles James, Philip Johnson, Ray Johnson, Doreen and Robert Manning, Agnes Martin, Gordon Newton, Claes Oldenburg, Ad Reinhardt, Dieter Rot, Alan Saret, Richard Tuttle, May Wilson, and Andy Warhol.
Writings by Wagstaff consist of "Looking at Modern Art" prepared for the Trinity College Reading Program, and an untitled, undated piece about multiplicity in art. Among the writings by other authors are Bruce Bennard's "The Photographer Rediscovered," "Pop Art" by Henry Geldzahler, and "Collecting Photographs" by Bonnie Barrett Stretch.
Miscellaneous records are drawings by Bruce Kleinsmith, a print by Harold Paris and artists' resumes. Also included is a costume consisting of a stuffed devil's tail and two red silk caps connected by a long sash, all in a matching red silk bag.
Among the printed material are books, exhibition catalogs and prospectuses, periodicals, press releases, reproductions, and a variety of other printed items relating to photography and art.
Photographs consist largely of copy prints and a small number of original prints. Also included are a few images of exhibition installations and other miscellaneous subjects. There are no portraits of Samuel J. Wagstaff among the photographs of people. Identified individuals include: Bella Abzug, Peter Allen, Michael Collins, Angela Davis, Candy Darling, Wendell Ford, Joseph Hirshhorn, W. A. Huffman, David Love, Marc Miller, Bettie Ringma, and Andy Warhol.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 5 series.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1932-1986 (Boxes 1-3, 8, OV 9-10; 2.5 linear ft.)
Series 2: Writings, 1961-1983 (Box 3; 0.2 linear ft.)
Series 3: Miscellaneous Papers and Artifacts, 1970s-1980s (Box 3; 0.2 linear ft.)
Series 4: Printed Material, circa 1914-1988 (Boxes 3-8, OV 11; 3.2 linear ft.)
Series 5: Photographs, 1975-1982 (Boxes 7-8; 0.1 linear ft.)
Basen, Dan,1939-; Brecht, George; Byars, James Lee; De Maria, Walter, 1935-; Di Suvero, Mark, 1933-; Fine, Albert M.; Flavin, Dan, 1933-; Halprin, Anna; Hartigan, Grace; James, Charles, d. 1978; Johnson, Philip, 1906-; Johnson, Ray, 1927-; Manning, Doreen; Manning, Robert; Martin, Agnes, 1912-; Newton, Gordon; Oldenburg, Claes, 1929-; Reinhardt, Ad, 1913-1967; Roth, Dieter, 1930-1998; Saret, Alan, 1944-; Tuttle, Richard, 1941-; Warhol, Andy, 1928-; Wilson, Mary F.; Art dealers--New York (State)--New York; Art, Modern; Art--Collectors and collecting--New York (State)--New York; Artists--United States; Curators--New York (State)--New York; Drawings; Fluxus (Group of artists); Photographs; Photographs--Collectors and collecting--United States; Photography
- Correspondence, 1932-1986; Series 1; (Boxes 1-3, 8, OV 9-10; 2.5 linear ft.)
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries. Correspondence in each subseries is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  1.1: Correspondence with Artists and Others, 1932-1975
  1.2: Correspondence Concerning Photography, 1957-1985
  - Correspondence with Artists and Others, 1932-1986; 1.1
    Scope and Contents note
    This subseries consists almost exclusively of incoming letters with a few carbon copies of Wagstaff's outgoing letters. There are a large number of illustrated letters, and many letters have printed items, photographs, and artwork as attachments.
    Correspondence is with artists and others such as curators, arts organizations, galleries, and museums. The series reflects the diversity of contemporary American art and includes letters from individuals associated with the abstract expressionist, Fluxus, pop, earth, conceptual, and minimalist art movements. Wagstaff's importance as a collector and curator and his generosity to, and interest in, artists is evident from the large number of invitations to view and critique work, requests for fellowship and grant recommendations, and thank you notes from artists to whom he extended financial or moral support. Among the most prolific correspondents found here are: Dan Basen, George Brecht, James Lee Byars, Walter de Maria, Mark Di Suvero, Albert Fine, Dan Flavin, Ann Halprin, Grace Hartigan, Charles James, Philip Johnson, Ray Johnson, Doreen and Robert Manning, Agnes Martin, Gordon Newton, Claes Oldenburg, Ad Reinhardt, Dieter Rot, Alan Saret, Richard Tuttle, May Wilson, and Andy Warhol. Items of note are James Lee Byars's letters, many of which are extremely large and written on unusual surfaces such as clear plastic and pink toilet tissue, and a letter from Thomas Hart Benton that describes the early work of Jackson Pollock. Also included are many illustrated letters and examples of mail art. Some of the Byars letters could not be digitized due to their extreme size.
    - Abish, Cecile - Balkin, Steve, 1932-1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Abish, Cecile
      Acconci, Vito
      Albers, Josef and Anni
      Alexander, William H.
      Alley, Ronald
      Alternative Press
      Anadine [?]
      Andre, Carl
      Artists Against the Expressway
      Artists Equity Association of New York, Inc.
      Artworkers Coalition
      Audouin, R.
      Avery, Milton
      B., Timothy
      Babee, Victor
      Balkin, Steve
      Balloon Newspaper (see: Kleinsmith, Bruce and Phillip Silbert)
    - Basen, Dan, 1962-1969, undated; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - Benton, Thomas Hart - Bolles, Robert, 1962-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Benton, Thomas Hart
      Berg, Harriet
      Bissinger, Karl
      Bolles, Robert
    - Brecht, George, 1962-1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Brodie, Gandy - Bultman, Fritz, 1962-1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Brodie, Gandy
      Brussez, Casell
      Bultman, Fritz
    - Byars, James Lee, 1963-1977, undated; (9 folders; see also: Box 8 and OV 9-10; partially scanned) (Box 1, Folder 7-15)
    - Caesar, Doris - deKooning, Elaine, 1961-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Caesar, Doris
      Calcagno, Larry
      Carter, Will
      Castell, Leo
      Chauvelin, Jean
      Collins, R.
      Crampton, Rollin
      Cudahy, William
      Cumming, Robert C.
      Cunningham, Merce
      deKooning, Elaine
    - De Maria, Walter, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - DeNiro, Bob - Dienes, Sam, 1962-1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
      DeNiro, Bob
      Denison, Mary
      Diamondstein, Barbaralee D.
      Dienes, Sam
    - Di Suvero, Mark 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Dowden, Jerry - Etherington, Thea, 1932-1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Dowden, Jerry
      Duchamp, Marcel
      Duncan, Tom
      Dwan Gallery
      Edgerly, Josh
      Edlich, Dr. and Mrs. Theodore J., Jr.
      Edwards, James
      Eilshemius, Louis (to Rev. Kelly)
      Eisenhauer, Lou
      Emanuel, Jerry
      Esneon, Rosa
      Etherington, Thea
    - Fine, Albert M., 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Fischbach Gallery - Fitzhugh, J. Perry, 1963-1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Fischbach Gallery
      Fitzhugh, J. Perry
    - Flavin, Dan, 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Fogg Art Museum - Hague, Raoul, 1962-1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Fogg Art Museum, Harvard University
      Freedman, Lewis
      Fulbright, J. W.
      Gabo, Naum
      Geldzahler, Henry
      Geoffrey, Jawaid Iqbal
      Gerber, Toni
      Gerhard, Gary
      Gernreich, Rudi
      Gill, George
      Ginnever, Chuck
      Goldowsky, Noah
      Goosen, Eugene
      Green Gallery
      Green, Samuel
      Guggenheim, Peggy
      Guston, Philip
      Hague, Raoul
    - Halprin, Ann, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Hartigan, Grace, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Hay, Deborah - Jacobson, Helen, 1962-1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Hay, Deborah
      Hayes, David
      Heatherington, Frances
      Hennessy, Timothy
      Herms, George
      Hess, John
      Higgins, Richard C.
      Hillman, Kay
      Hiroshige
      Hochman, Murray
      Hollander, John
      Holmes, Arlaine
      Horwitt, Will
      Hoving, Thomas
      Howe, Nelson
      Hudt, Bob
      Indianapolis Art League Foundation
      Isobe, Yukihisa
      Jacobson, Helen
    - James, Charles, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Johnson, Philip, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Johnson, Ray, 1960-1965; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 30-32)
    - Johnson, Ray, 1966-1983; (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
    - Johnstone, Jill - Kent, William, 1962-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Johnstone, Jill
      Judd, Donald
      Kallmann, Gerhard
      Kaprow, Allan
      Karp, Ivan
      Katzen, Lila
      Kaufman, Don
      Kelly, Ellsworth
      Kent, William
    - Kleinsmith, Bruce and Phillip Siebert ( The Balloon Newspaper), 1970-1971, undated; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
    - Koch, Karl - Lytle, Richard, 1962-1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Koch, Karl
      Kochno, Boyi
      Koutroulis, Aris
      Krasner, Lee
      Lane, Alvin S.
      Lichtenstein, Roy
      Lindsay, John V.
      Lowry, Bruce
      Lytle, Richard
    - Magar, Anthony - Mamson, Charlie, 1961-1964, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Magar, Anthony
      Malabin, Dr. and Mrs. Burnett
      Mallary, Robert
      Mamson, Charlie
    - Manning, Doreen and Robert, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Markopoulos Gregory J. - Marlowe, Alan, 1964, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Martin, Agnes 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Mazelow Gallery - Montez, Mario, 1962-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Mazelow Gallery
      McCoy, Sanford
      McFadden, Elizabeth
      McIntosh, Michael
      Mellon, Paul
      Metznik
      Michael, David
      Middleman, Raoul
      Millonzi, Victor
      Montez, Mario
    - Morris, Robert, 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Mouse, Stanley - Newman, Barnett, 1963-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Mouse, Stanley
      Murphy, Greg
      Museum of Modern Art
      Myers, John Bernard
      Nakian, Robert
      Nesbitt, Lowell
      Nevelson, Mike and Flo
      New Britain Development Commission, Design Review Committee
      Newman, Barnett
    - Newton, Gordon, 1970-1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - New York City, Department of Parks - Oenslager, Donald, 1964-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
      New York City, Department of Parks
      Noguchi, Isamu
      Nozynski, John H.
      Oenslager, Donald
    - Oldenburg, Claes, 1962-1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Ono, Yoko - Parsons, Harold Woodbury, 1963-1969, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Ono, Yoko
      Orr, David
      Ortman, George
      Paik, Nam June
      Parker, Ray
      Parsons, Betty
      Parsons, Harold Woodburry
    - Pasadena Art Museum - Prentice, David, 1962-1971 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Pasadena Art Museum
      Pavie, Martine
      Perrey, Beati
      Petersburg Press
      Pollock, Ann
      Porter, Fairfield
      Prentice, David
    - Rackliffe, Howard - Reid, Terry, 1964-1971 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Rackliffe, Howard
      Ranier, Yvonne
      Read, A.
      Rebay, Hilla V.
      Reichard, Stephen B.
      Reid, Terry
    - Reinhardt, Ad 1966-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Rezial [?], Jeanne - Rosenblum, Robert, 1962-1972, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Rezial [?], Jeanne
      Robbins, Danny and Genie
      Robbins, Matthew L. ("Pop")
      Rose, Barbara
      Rosenboom, David
      Rosenblum, Robert
    - Rot, Diter, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Ruscha, Ed - Santon, Chuck, 1965-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
      Ruscha, Ed
      Sabol, Audrey
      Sandback, Fred
      Santon, Chuck
    - Saret, Allan, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Scanga, Italo - Smith, David, 1962-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Scanga, Italo
      Schapiro, Meyer
      Schatz Little Green Books
      Schneemann, Carolee
      Scull, Mr. and Mrs. Robert C.
      Shapiro, David
      Shelter Enterprises
      Sidney Janis Gallery
      Siebert, Phillip (see: Kleinsmith, Bruce and Phillip Siebert)
      Shipman, Mary
      Simonis, Paul
      Smith, Anthony
      Smith, David
    - Solomon, Sidney R. - Tremaine, Emily, 1963-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Solomon, Sidney R.
      Staffaldt, Marianne
      Stankiewicz, Richard
      Starkey, Alexander
      Steinweg, Klara
      Stephen, Rudi
      Stocker, Walter
      Stocklander
      Streeter, Tal
      Strider, Marjorie
      Sugarman, George
      Sullivan, William J.
      Swenson, G.
      Sybil Shearer Company
      Tamm, Patrick
      Thomas, Peter
      Tremaine, Emily
    - Tuttle, Richard, 1962-1986, undated; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
    - Tversky, Leonard - Von Schlegell, David, 1962-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Tversky, Leonard
      Tyler, R.
      Union Carbide Corporation
      Universal Limited Art Editions
      Updike, John
      Urban, Reva
      Vicente, Esteban
      Vilcesu, Cornelia
      Von Schlegell, David
    - Wadowski, Diane - Wardlaw, George, 1963-1964, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Wadowski, Diane
      Waldrop, Keith
      Wallace, Gerald
      Wardlaw, George
    - Warhol, Andy, 1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Waterman, Doug - Whitman, Robert, 1955-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
      Waterman, Doug
      Watts, Robert
      Westerman, H. C.
      Weyand, Richard
      Whitman, Robert
    - Wilson, May, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Wise, Howard - Zeidenberg, Olaf, Group Signature, 1963-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
      Wise, Howard
      Wolff, Christian
      Wood, Charles B., III
      Young, La Monte
      Zawisa, Bernard
      Zazeela, Marian
      Zeidenberg, Olaf
      Group Signature
    - Unsigned, 1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Illegible, 1962-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Unknown, A-Z, 1957-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
      Adrian
      Alain
      Bell
      Billy and Ogden
      D. K.
      David
      Deborah, David, Savannah
      Ellen
      Ellie
      Hooaf [?]
      J. H.
      Jim
      John
      Judy
      Michael
      T. S.
      Tom
    - Oversized Byars, James Lee, undated; (see also Box 1 F7-15) (Box 8 (sol), Folder 1)
    - Oversized Byars, James Lee, 1968, undated; (see also Box 1 F7-15; partially scanned) (Box OV 9)
    - Oversized Byars, James Lee, undated; (see also Box 1 F7-15; partially scanned) (Box OV 10)
  - Correspondence concerning Photography, 1957-1985; 1.2
    Correspondence concerning photography is primarily of a routine nature and consists mainly of letters from photographers, photographic dealers, and curators. With one exception, all letters from Ansel Adams are photocopies.
    - Adams, Ansel - Averell, William H., 1957-1985, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
      Adams, Ansel
      Afterimage
      Agnoli, Kathleen
      A.I.R. Gallery
      Alexander, Nina
      Allen, John
      American Federation of Arts
      American Photographer
      American Society of Appraisers
      Andrews, Mary Ellen
      Apeiron Workshops, Inc.
      Aperture
      Armstrong, Tom
      Art and Antiques
      Artforum
      Art in America
      Art Institute of Chicago
      Artists in the City
      ARTtnews
      Arts Commission of the City of Detroit
      Arts Council of Great Britain
      Askin, Lucille Bunin
      Auer, Anna
      Auerbacher, Dominique
      Australian National Gallery
      Averell, William H.
    - Badger, Gerry - Byhart [?], Mark, 1974-1984, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
      Badger, Gemy
      Baker, Krystyna
      Baltimore Museum of Art
      Bankhead, Judy
      Bard College
      Baron, Steve
      Barron, Susan
      Basilico, Gabriele
      Beaton, Cecil
      Beckwith, Carol
      Bell, Deborah
      Bell Editions
      Ben-David, Aaron
      Benton-Harris, John
      Berman, Zeke
      Bernstein, M.
      Bertha Urdang Gallery
      Betsch, William
      Bishop, Jim
      Bishop, Robert C.
      Block, G.
      Block, Helen
      Bloom, Phillip
      Blos, Stephen
      Blue Sky, Oregon Center for the Photographic Arts
      Blue Swan Gallery
      Bondi, Inge
      Bootz, Antoine
      Brewer, Caldwell
      Brigidi, Stephen
      Brooks, Ellen
      Brooks Jackson Gallery Iolas
      Brown, Lawrie ( see: Dawson, Robert and Lawrie Brown)
      Brown, Robert L.
      Brown University
      Buck, Ken
      Buckland, David
      Buscaglia Castellani Art Gallery
      Byhart [?], Mark
    - California Book Auction Co. - Curtis Art Project, 1975-1984 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      California Book Auction Co.
      Callaway Editions
      Canadian Center for Architecture
      Capa, Cornell
      Carl Siembab Gallery of Photography
      Caslin, Jean
      Castelli, Leo (see: Judson, Bill and Leo Castelli)
      Cavanagh, John P.
      Center for International Studies
      Charles Apfelbaum Books
      Charles P. Wood III, Antiquarian Bookseller
      Charlesmith [?], Sarah
      Christie's (London)
      Chrysler Museum
      Cialdella, Gary
      Clatworthy Colorvues
      Clergue, Lucien
      Clift, William
      Clough, Charlie
      Cohain, Yossaif
      Collectors' Center
      Complete Book of Photographers
      Conniff, Gregory
      Cooper-Hewitt Museum
      Cooper, Thomas Joshua
      Copland, Aaron
      Cox, Henry
      Cratsley, Bruce
      Imogen Cunningham Trust (see also: Friends of Imogen Cunningham)
      Curtis Art Project
    - Da Capo Press, Inc. - Estabrook Reed, 1976-1985, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
      Da Capo Press, Inc.
      Daitz, Howard C.
      David Lawrence Bauman, Bookseller
      Davies, Bevan
      Davies, Thomas L.
      Davis, Douglas
      Dawson, Robert and Lawrie Brown
      Dayton, Sue
      De La Peña Books
      De Lellis, Keith Douglas
      de Monzi, Piero
      Desvergnes, Alain
      Detroit Institute of Arts
      Dewan, Janet
      Diamondstein, Barbaralee
      Diniz, Pepe
      Dixon, Penelope A.
      Donovan, Kevin
      Dotter, Earl
      Eaton/Shoen Gallery
      Edith C. Blum Art Institute
      Elisofon, Elin
      Elsie Meyer Gallery
      Enos, Chris
      Estabrook, Reed
    - Falk, Peter - Frizot, Michel, 1979-1984, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Falk, Peter
      Famous Posters International, Inc.
      Farbman, Suzy
      Fay Gold Gallery
      Feiler, Jo Alison
      Ferguson, Larry S.
      Field, Dick
      Fogel, Harris
      Fogg Art Museum
      Font, Paul and John Ritchie
      Ford, Charles Henri
      Ford, Colin
      Ford Foundation
      Fraenkel Gallery
      Franklin Institute Science Museum
      Frazer, Jim
      Freidus/Ordlover Gallery, Inc.
      Friends of Imogene Cunningham (see also: Imogen Cunningham Trust)
      Friends of Photography
      Frizot, Michel
    - Galerie Fiolet - Gurner, Fred, 1975-1983, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Galerie Fiolet
      Galerie Gmurzynska
      Galerie Max Hetzler
      Gallery Nature Morte
      Gallery of World Photography Project
      Gates, Jeffrey S.
      Gelabert, Edgar
      Gelpke, André
      George Robert Minkoff, Inc.
      Gettner, Noah
      Goode, Paul B.
      Gottheim, Lary
      Gozu, Masao
      Granada Television Limited
      Graphics International Ltd.
      G. Ray Hawkins Gallery, Inc.
      Gray, W. Brooke
      Greathouse, T.
      Gurner, Fred
    - Halus, Siegfried - Iverson, Brad, 1971-1985, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Halus, Sigfried
      Hambourg, Maria
      Harbutt, Charles
      Harm Bouckaert Gallery
      Harold Reed Gallery